



Taiabur Rahman

O Home: Village+Post Office- Modinabad, Police Station- Koyra, Dist-Khulna, 9290, Khulna, Bangladesh

Email: <u>taiaburbd@gmail.com</u> **A Phone:** (+880) 01914651671

Gender: Male **Date of birth:** 17/10/1990 **Nationality:** Bangladeshi

ABOUT ME

Almost over 8 years I started my career as a software developer, in my ongoing working experience met with the medical sector. I develop a software Hospital information management system. With my long experience as a software developer and software engineer. I'm continuing my education with the Erasmus+ program for Medical Imaging and Application (MAIA).

WORK EXPERIENCE

[31/12/2020 – Current]

Assistant IT Manager

Vision Eye Hospital

City: Dhaka

Country: Bangladesh

[05/09/2018 - 23/07/2020]

Higher education research assistant

Tianjin University

City: Tianjin Country: China

[10/2017 - 08/2018]

Software Engineer

Vision Eye Hospital

City: Dhaka

Country: Bangladesh

[18/10/2019 - 22/07/2020]

Web application developer

SystemBind Consulting & IT Services Inc. (Freelance job)

City: Toronto Country: Canada Remote Jobs

Department: Web application development team

[31/07/2016 – 29/01/2017] **Web application developer**

Make Good Media (Freelance job)

City: Toronto Country: Canada

Company Location: Toronto

Department: Software Development

Web: https://twitter.com/makegoodmediato

[31/12/2015 – Current]

Application developer

Agile Tech Solution (part time job)

City: Dhaka

Country: Bangladesh

[31/01/2017 - 26/09/2017]

Software Engineer

Aptronix Ltd.

City: Dhaka

Country: Bangladesh Location: Mirpur, Dhaka

Department: Web application development team

[31/12/2015 - 29/07/2016] **Software Engineer**

Coderment Limited

City: Dhaka

Country: Bangladesh

Location: Mohakhali DOHS, Dhaka

Department: Web application development team

Web: http://www.coderment.com

[13/04/2014 - 29/12/2015]

Web application developer

APOGEE IT

City: Dhaka

Country: Bangladesh

Location: Panthapath, Dhaka

Department: Web application development team

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[07/09/2022 - 30/07/2024]

Medical Imaging and Application (MAIA)

Erusmus+ Join Master Program https://maiamaster.udg.edu/

Address: Spain

[08/09/2022 - 30/01/2023]

MSc in Computer Vision

University of Burgundy https://www.u-bourgogne.fr

Address: France

[05/09/2018 - 29/07/2020]

MSC in Computer Software

Tianjin University http://www.tju.edu.cn/english/index.htm

Address: Peiyangyuan Campus: No.135 Yaguan Road, Haihe Education Park, 300350,

Tianjin, China

Oracle Certified Professional (OCP)

IBCS-PRIMAX Software (Bangladesh) Ltd. https://www.ibcs-primax.com

Address: House- 6/2, (Level: 4 & 6) Kazi Nazrul Islam Road, Block- F, Lalmatia Housing

Estate,, 1207, Dhaka, Bangladesh

[30/09/2010 - 01/02/2014]

BSC in Computer Science and Engineering

Bangladesh University https://bu.edu.bd

Address: 15/1 Iqbal Rd, 1207, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Final grade: 3.28/4.00

[26/12/2005 - 12/2009]

Diploma in Agriculture

Agriculture Training Institute Daulatpur Khulna

Address: Daulatpur Khulna, 9202, Khulna, Bangladesh

Final grade: 3.48/4.00

Dakhil Examiniation

Kalna Aminia Fazil Madrasah-Bangladesh Madrasah Education Board

Address: 9290, Koyra, Bangladesh

Final grade: 3.83/5.00

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Bengali

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Chinese

LISTENING AT READING AT WRITING AT

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Database: SQL, Oracle | SQL (MySQL) | PHP Language | MySQL | DevOps with CI | AWS Web Services | RESTful api | Git | JSON | Web Development | JavaScript | SQL | Vue CLI | Medical Imaging | Github | Image Processing, Image Analysis, Image Segmentation | programming language PYTHON

DRIVING LICENCE

Motorbikes: A Cars:

HONOURS AND AWARDS

[05/09/2018] **Tianjin Government Scholarship 2018 Awarding institution:** Tianjin Government (Local Government of PR China)

I really honored to award Tianjin Government Scholarship 2018

[01/09/2019] **Tianjin Government Scholarship 2019 Awarding institution:** Tianjin Government (Local Government of PR China)

I really honored to award Tianjin Government Scholarship 2019

[01/09/2020] **Tianjin Government Scholarship 2020 Awarding institution:** Tianjin Government (Local Government of PR China)

> I really honored to award Tianjin Government Scholarship 2020, But I can't enjoy Scholars hip 2020 scholarship facilities due to COVID-19

NETWORKS AND MEMBERSHIPS

IEEE IEEE has a global presence with seven offices internationally.

Bangladesh Computer Samity (BCS) Dhaka, Bangladesh